Meet Rainbow Dash and Rarity the Unicorn!
My Little Pony: The Runaway Rainbow is a animation,
adventure, fantasy film directed by Victor Dal Chele.
Rainbow Dash loves the time of year when Ponyville and Breezie
Blossom are all about celebrating rainbows.
Meanwhile in a new magical place called Unicornia, Rarity is being taught how to be a
Unicorn Princess and the importance of making the first rainbow of the season.
But she is quite a little rascal and embarks on an incredible ride, a huge
adventure (with lots of mishaps) as she tries to get back to Unicornia.
Rarity soon realizes that getting home in time to create the first rainbow
of season is not an easy thing to do --- but it is fun!
Sweetberry (voice), played by Kathleen Barr.
Brights Brightly (voice), played by Maryke Hendrikse.
Pinkie Pie (voice), played by Janyse Jaud.
Sunny Daze / Coconut Cream (voice), played by Adrienne Carter.
Spike (voice), played by Brian Drummond.
Zipzee (voice), played by Andrea Libman.
My Little Pony Crystal Princess: The Runaway Rainbow is a 2006 direct-to-video animated musical fantasy adventure film
produced by SD Entertainment and distributed by Paramount Home Entertainment in association with Hasbro.
The film is the third feature in the third incarnation of the My Little Pony
series and the second film to promote the Crystal Princess line.
Unlike The Princess Promenade, the film has been criticized.
The DVD also features two more animated features, Greetings from Unicornia and Friends
are Never Far Away, which was originally released on video in 2005.
The Runaway Rainbow was made available on hubworld.com (a successor of Hasbro's MonkeyBarTV website),
alongside My Little Pony: A Very Minty Christmas and My Little Pony: The Princess Promenade.
But they were removed from the site later.
The movie has been reissued in the 2-disc DVD collection My Little Pony: Classic Movie Collection,
alongside The Princess Promenade, Dancing in the Clouds and Friends are Never Far Away.
Alongside The Princess Promenade and Twinkle Wish Adventure, the film premiered on August
8, 2014 on the Hub Network after its "My Little Pony Mega Mare-athon".
According to Broadway World, the "Mega Mare-athon" itself drew in 5.4 million viewers and has earned significant delivery growth on every demographic: Kids 2-11 (+134%), Girls 2-11
(+179%), Kids 6-11 (+169%), Girls 6-11 (+216%), Adults 18-49 (+111%), Women 18-49 (+146%), Adults 25-54 (+74%), Women 25-54 (+76%), Persons 2+ (+124%) and Households (+98%).
The film explores themes of anthropomorphism, based on toy, unicorn.
The tone is lighthearted.